One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
I Made It Here
Buraya Kadar Başardım
Four hundred years of fighting had come to an end at last,
Skypiea'nın 400 yılık savaşı sona erdi...
and the Skypieans continued their celebration for days on end.
ve bütün her yeri saran kutlama gece boyunca devam etti.
I... I... I can't drink any more...
A... A... Artık içemem...
There they are!
İşte oradalar!
Hey!
Hey!
What is it?
Ne?
Nami, wake everyone up!
Nami, herkesi uyandır!
Why?
Niye?
We're gonna steal the gold and run!
Biraz altın çalıp kaçacağız!
There's gold?!
Altın var mı?!
Dummy! Keep it down!
Aptal! Sessiz ol!
What do you mean "dummy"?! You're louder than I am!
Aptal mı?! Benden daha gürültücüsün!
Louder than you?! You're the loud one!
Ben mi? Asıl bağıra çağıra konuşan sensin!
What?! You're calling me loud when you're being super-duper loud?!
Nasıl yani?! Ortalığı inlettiğin hâlde bana mı gürültücü diyorsun?!
It's your voice that's super-mega-ultra loud!
Senin sesin tam anlamıyla kulakları sağır edecek cinsten!
No way! The only reason I'm talking so loud is because you're yelling!
Saçmalama! Yüksek sesle konuşmamın tek nedeni senin bağırman!
You were yelling first!
İlk bağıran sendin! Kesin sesinizi! Uyuyamıyorum!
So what?! You're still the loud one!
Ne?! Hâlâ bağırıyorsun!
Not me! It's you!
Hayır! Sen bağırıyorsun!
Usopp hit me!
Usopp bana vurdu!
I'm a delicate lady! I wouldn't yell with my mouth wide open, would I?!
Ben zarif bir hanımefendiyim! Ağzımı açıp bağıracak değilim ya!
What?!
Ne?!
I'd never do that!
Bunu asla yapmam!
See? See?! Your mouth is wide open!
Bak gördün mü?! Ağzın kocaman açık!
Don't accuse me of that!
Beni bununla itham etme!
Geez, wake up, sleepyhead!
Hadi uyan artık, uykucu!
But you did hit me!
Ama bana vurdun!
That's because you ticked me off!
Beni kızdırdığın için!
Right here, I felt it!
Tam buraya, hissettim!
Nami! Good morning!
Nami-san! Günaydın!
Yeah, yeah... Keep telling yourself that, dummy.
He he... Öyle sanmaya devam et, budala.
I just said you don't have to yell!
Bağırmana gerek yok dedim ya!
Oh? It's not morning yet!
Ha? Daha sabah olmamış!
What do you mean, "dummy"?!
"Budala" mı?!
Blue Sea people sure like to party, don't they?
Mavi Denizliler parti yapmayı çok seviyor, değil mi?
This is the fourth day in a row.
Hiç yorulmamış gibiler.
Their stamina is incredible.
Kesinlikle insan değiller.
So, that's the plan.
Evet, plan bu!
Okay, guys! It's not often that we get to visit a sky island!
Tamam, millet! Nadir bulunan bir yerdeyiz!
Make sure you don't leave with any regrets!
Arkanızda pişmanlık bırakmayın!
Chief! We found the golden bell!
Şef! Altın çanı bulduk!
What?!
Ne?!
Hey, are you serious?!
Hey, emin misin?!
Yeah. It's stuck on the fallen Giant Jack.
Evet. Devrilen Dev Jack'e takılmış.
We're pulling it out right now.
Şu anda herkes onu çekmeye çalışıyor!
If you can help, come to the western shore!
İyi olan herkes batı kıyısına!
Hurry! Get a move on!
Çabuk! En kısa sürede!
Alright! Gather everyone!
Tamam! Herkesi toplayın!
They found the bell!
Çanı bulduk!
Where?!
Nerede?!
At the western shore.
Batı kıyısında!
– Okay!
– Tamam!
Are you sure?!
Emin misin?!
Yeah! Hurry up already!
Evet! Acele edin artık!
Apparently it fell into the sea!
Belli ki denize düşmüş!
Yeah. Those who can move, gather at the western shore!
Evet. Hareket edebilen herkes batı kıyısında buluşsun!
They found the bell!
Çanı buldular!
It's at the western shore!
Batı kıyısında!
The bell...?
Çan...?
One more time!
Bir daha!
One, two...!
Bir, iki...!
Pull!
Çekin!
Dammit! We still don't have enough people.
Kahretsin! Yeterli insan gücümüz yok!
This is the pride of our ancestors—of Shandora.
Atalarımızın onuru— Shandora'nın yadigârı.
We'll do whatever it takes!
Ne gerekiyorsa yapacağız!
That's right!
Evet!
Give it all you got!
Tüm gücünüzle!
One more time! One, two...!
Bir daha! Bir, iki...!
Pull with all your might!
Tüm gücünüzle çekin!
Rubber band?! This is called a rubber band?!
Lastik bant mı?! Buna lastik bant mı deniyor?!
Yeah!
Evet!
Usopp's Rubber Bands of Doom did 90 percent of the damage to Giant Jack!
Usopp'un Ölümcül Lastik Bantları, Dev Jack'e hasarın yüzde 90'ını verdi!
– Whoa! – Whoa! Incredible!
– Vay! – Vay! İnanılmaz!
And I'm the only one in the world who has them.
Dünyada sadece bende var!
– Whoa! – Whoa! Amazing!
– Vay! – Vay! Müthiş!
But... let's put that aside for now. Next up is this iron sheet!
Ama bunu şimdilik bir kenara bırakalım. Sırada bu sac var!
Now, ladies and gentlemen! This is no ordinary iron sheet!
Şimdi, bayanlar ve baylar! Bu sıradan bir sac değil!
It's an iron sheet taken from our ship, the Going Merry, that's survived
Bu, Going Merry gemimizden alınan, Grand Line'ı ve Enel'in saldırılarını...
the Grand Line, as well as Enel's attacks! It's the "King of Iron Sheets"!
sağlam bir şekilde atlatmış bir sac! Bu "Sac'ların Kralı"!
How about it?! You guys want iron, right?
Ne dersiniz?! Sac ister misiniz?
Wanna trade me some dials for this?
Birkaç "dial" ile takas edebilirim!
No! I want this rubber band!
Hayır! Bu lastik bandı istiyorum!
I'll trade you for this rubber band!
Bununla takas edeceğiz!
I want one too! Can I have one?!
Ben de istiyorum! Başka var mı?!
Me too!
Ben de!
Whoa... Are they serious?!
Vay... Cidden mi?!
Give me one too!
Bana da ver!
Me too!
Bana da!
Shells! I got shells! Oh, yeah!
Deniz kabukları! Deniz kabuklarım var! Oh, evet!
Lucky, lucky! I got so lucky!
Şanslı, şanslı! Çok şanslıyım!
You sure are in a good mood, Usopp.
Çok keyiflisin, Usopp.
Did the trade go well?
Satışlar iyi miydi?
Hear that?
Bak, bak...
I got a ton of dials!
Bir sürü dial'ım var!
Just press here, and...
Sadece buraya bas ve...
out it comes!
olanları izle!
Good for you.
Aferin sana.
Good for me!
Aferin bana!
With this many dials, I can do all sorts of stuff!
Bu kadar dial ile her türlü şey yapabilirim!
The Usopp Factory will be running full steam!
Usopp Fabrikası olanca hızıyla gelişecek!
Hey, Zoro! What if I made your swords into melon-flavored scent swords?
Hey, Zoro! Ya kılıçlarını kavun aromalı kılıçlara dönüştürsem?
That would spice up your daily training!
Antrenmanların eğlenceli hâle gelir!
No thanks.
Yok kalsın.
Oh...
Oh...
Oh, yeah! I can upgrade Nami's Climate Baton!
Tabii ya! Nami'nin İklim Asası'nı geliştirebilirim!
And my slingshot will be better than ever!
Ve sapanım her zamankinden daha güçlü olacak!
So, where are Robin, Luffy, and the others?
Sahi, Robin, Luffy ve diğerleri nerede?
Luffy and the others are still inside. Robin went off somewhere.
Luffy ve diğerleri hâlâ içeride. Robin de bir yere gitti.
Well, I'll be... This snake sure is a sound sleeper.
Şey... O yılan deliksiz uyuyor.
He was dancing for days...
Bir kaç gün durmadan dans etti.
Wonder what he was so happy about.
Acaba neden o kadar mutluydu.
In any case, they should come out soon.
Her hâlükârda, hemen çıkmazlarsa...
He could be trouble if he wakes up.
yılan uyanacak ve işler kötüleşecek.
Huh?
Ha?
This sweetheart of a snake?
O uysal yılan mı?
Idiot! You just don't know what a pain he can be!
Sersem. Bu şeyin kızgın hâlini görmedin!
Like I said, you didn't see how pissed off this snake was.
Dediğim gibi, onu kızgınken görmediğin için öyle diyorsun!
This sweetheart of a snake?
O uysal yılan mı?
Alright, come on, Usopp!
Hey, dinliyor musun, Usopp?!
It was a tone dial!
Tone dial'dı!
Enough with the stupid gag!
Aptalca şakaları kes artık!
Yeah, it's stupid! It's really stupid!
Evet, aptalcaydı! Aptalca!
What the heck?! What does this snake eat?
Bu da ne?! Bu yılan ne yiyormuş böyle?
Are we there yet, Luffy?
Hâlâ bulamadın mı, Luffy?
Look! There it is!
Bakın! İşte burada!
Wow! Amazing!
Vay! Müthiş!
This is the real thing!
Sahiden gerçekmiş!
So pretty! Just like the ones we saw at the monkeys' house!
Çok güzel! Maymunların evinde gördüklerimizin aynısı!
See? See? See?!
Ya? Ya? Ya?!
Look at all this!
Şunlara bakın!
Isn't it awesome?!
Harika değil mi?!
So this is the golden...
Demek bu altın...
– How beautiful... – Incredible...
– Ne kadar güzel... – İnanılmaz...
– I didn't expect it to be this... – How magnificent.
– Böyle bir şey beklemiyordum... – Ne kadar muhteşem.
But one of the side columns is broken.
Ama yan sütunlardan biri kırık.
Yeah, it's been through a lot.
Evet ama yapacak bir şey yok.
Hey! Look there.
Hey! Şuna bakın.
So this is... the poneglyph...
O... poneglif...
The stone that our ancestors risked the city to protect!
Atalarımızın korumak için canını verdiği taş!
So what's written on it, Chief?
Peki ne yazıyor, Şef?
It isn't for us to know...
Bilmesek de olur...
We just...
Biz sadece...
"Hold the truth in your heart, and speak not of it.
"Gerçeği içinde sakla, ağzını sıkı tut.
We are the ones who weave history...
Bizler, büyük çanın yankılarıyla...
with the sounding of the grand bell..."
tarihi dokuyanlarız..."
How do you know those words?
O sözleri nereden biliyorsun?
They were carved on the Shandian ruins.
Shandia kalıntılarına işlenmişlerdi.
So you were the guardians who protected this for generations.
Yani nesiller boyu bunu koruyanlar sizmişsiniz.
Could it be... You can read those symbols?!
Yani... Bu sembolleri okuyabiliyor musun?!
Poseidon, the ancient weapon named after a god...
Bir tanrının adıyla anılan antik bir silah, Poseidon.
Its location...
Onun konumu hakkında...
What?! What's that?!
Ne?! O da ne?!
"Ancient"?!
"Antik" mi?!
Ancient weapon?
Antik silah mı?
Why would they write something like that?!
Niye öyle bir şey yazsın ki?!
Yeah...
Evet...
Another weapon... different from the Pluton I read about in Alabasta...
Bir silah daha... Alabasta'daki Pluton'dan farklı.
To think that such dangerous things
Dünyanın bir köşesinde...
still slumber somewhere in the world...!
hâlâ böyle tehlikeli şeylerin uykuda olması...!
I should've known better.
Tam bir hayal kırıklığı.
This isn't what I've been searching for.
Aradığım şey bu değildi.
Hey, you!
Hey, sen!
Aren't there more of those symbols engraved next to it?!
Şu taraftakiler de aynı dilde yazılmamış mı?!
What?!
Ne?!
"Gol D. Roger"...!
"Gol D. Roger"...!
What is this?!
Bu ne?!
I made it here.
Buraya kadar başardım.
I will guide this text to the ends of the world.
Bu sözleri dünyanın öbür ucuna götüreceğim.
Pirate Gol D. Roger.
Korsan Gol D. Roger.
The King of the Pirates...!
Korsanlar Kralı...!
Could this mean that he came to this sky island, too?!
Bu, gökyüzü adasına geldiği anlamına mı geliyor?!
No, more importantly, how did he know this script?
Hayır, en önemlisi, nasıl bu dilde yazabilmiş?
Did I hear "Roger"?
"Roger" mı yazıyor?
You know him?!
Tanıyor musun?!
He's a Blue Sea pirate who came to this sky over twenty years ago.
Yirmi yılı aşkın bir süre önce, Mavi Deniz'den buraya gelen bir korsandı.
So his name is engraved there?
Oraya onun ismi mi kazınmış?
Yes.
Evet.
I don't know how he reached this bell...
Bu çana nasıl ulaşmış, bilmiyorum...
but this is definitive proof that he did.
ama bu, onun yaptığının kesin kanıtı.
Come to think of it, there are two kinds of poneglyph stones.
Düşündüm de, iki çeşit poneglif taşı var.
Ones with information, and others that mark locations.
Bazıları bilgi içeriyor, bazıları konum gösteriyor.
This is the type with information.
Bu, bilgi içerenlerden.
"I made it here.
"Buraya kadar başardım."
I will guide this text to the ends of the world."
"Bu metni dünyanın öbür ucuna götüreceğim."
Guide this text...
Bu metni götüreceğim...
Guide...
Götüreceğim...
Could it be...?!
Yoksa...
Could the Rio Poneglyph be...?!
Rio Poneglifi'nden mi bahsediyor?! Rio Poneglifi: Gerçek tarihi metin.
Chief...
Şef...
This poneglyph has already fulfilled its role!
Bu poneglif, çoktan amacına hizmet etmiş.
It has?!
Amaç mı?!
Yes.
Evet.
I believe the informational poneglyphs scattered around the world
Dünyanın dört bir yanına dağılmış olan bilgi ponegliflerini birleştirerek,
can be combined into a single text that will fill in the Void Century.
Kayıp Yüzyıl'ı dolduracak tek bir metne ulaşılabileceğine inanıyorum.
In other words, connecting the full text creates...
Kısaca, tüm metnin birleştirilmesi,
something never seen before: the Rio Poneglyph.
henüz var olmayan Rio Poneglifi'ni ortaya çıkaracak.
Gol D. Roger, King of the Pirates,
Korsanlar Kralı, Gol D. Roger'ın...
must have delivered this text to its destination.
bu metni hedefine ulaştırdığından eminim.
So it's no longer...
Artık...
Then...
O zaman...
Hm?
Hm?
We... don't have to... fight any longer?
Biz... artık... savaşmak zorunda değil miyiz?
I see... So the wish of our ancestors has been fulfilled?
Anlıyorum... Atalarımızın dileği gerçekleşmiş mi?
– Chief!
– Şef!
Are you all right?!
İyi misiniz?!
Good... Good... So our duty has been fulfilled!
Şükürler, şükürler olsun... Görevimiz tamamlandı!
Yes.
Evet.
Which means I, too,
Yani ben de,
have to guide the text on the poneglyphs I've read...
şimdiye kadar okuduğum ponegliflerdeki metinleri...
to the end of the Grand Line... to Laugh Tale...
Grand Line'ın sonundaki Laugh Tale'e götürmeliyim!
Young lady, that straw hat boy gives me the same feeling Roger once did.
Genç hanım, o hasır şapkalı çocuk, bana Roger'ı andıran bir his veriyor.
But perhaps it's just my imagination.
Ama belki de sadece hayal gücümdür.
His name is Monkey D. Luffy.
Adı Monkey D. Luffy.
He never fails to keep my interest.
İlgimi her zaman canlı tutuyor.
D? I see. So they share that letter in their names.
D mi? Anlıyorum. İsimlerinde aynı harfi paylaşıyorlar.
Yes... and I'm sure it's quite important to our history.
Evet... ve eminim ki tarihimiz için oldukça önemli olacak.
By the way, miss...
Affedersiniz...
You all wanted gold, right?
Altın istiyordunuz, değil mi?
You said it's more valuable than vearth in the Blue Sea.
Mavi Deniz'deki vearth'den daha değerliydi demiştiniz.
Yes.
Öyle.
Since we can't give you the bell,
Size çanı veremeyiz ama...
how about the bell column?
çan sütununa ne dersiniz?
That's a good idea!
Bu harika bir fikir!
We have to show our appreciation to you guys somehow, you know.
Sonuçta, sizlere bir şekilde teşekkür etmemiz gerekiyor.
That's right!
Doğru!
We insist!
Israr ediyoruz!
Are you sure?! They'll be happy to hear that!
Emin misiniz?! Bunu duyunca çok sevinecekler!
Yes!
Evet!
Alright, then! Let's bring this to the Blue Sea people!
Hadi o zaman! Bunu Mavi Deniz insanlarına götürelim!
Wrap it with cloth! It's hard to carry!
Yan taraflarına geçin! Taşıması zor olacak!
Let's give it to the people who saved our land!
Ülkemizin kurtarıcılarına vereceğiz!
Man, this thing's huge...
Ama bu çok büyük.
What's Robin doing? She's late!
Robin ne yapıyor? Gecikti.
Oh, man! I'm hungry!
Eyvah, acıkıyorum!
This place sure emptied out. What's going on?
Ortalıkta kimse kalmamış. Neler oluyor?
Where did all those guerrillas and angels go?
Gerillalar ve melekler nereye gitti?
Well, it's better they aren't here. They'll chase us if they find out!
Burada olmamaları daha iyi. Öğrenirlerse bizi kovalarlar!
We're about to steal all this gold and make a run for it.
Sonuçta altın çalıp kaçıyoruz.
They won't just let us escape!
Buna izin vermeyecekler!
Nami and Conis are preparing the ship, but we still have to hurry.
Nami ve Conis gemiyi hazırlıyor, biz de vakit kaybetmemeliyiz.
Before that, Sanji, do we have something to eat?
Bu arada Sanji, yiyecek bir şeyin var mı?
Yeah, on the ship.
Evet, gemide var.
But you've gotta have a little snack to munch on, right?
Ama bir şeyler atıştırmak lazım, değil mi?
Gimme!
Versene! Can sıkıcı!
I can't give you what I don't have! Let it go!
Yok dedim ya, beni rahat bırak! Niye o kadını beklemek zorundayız?
I'm gonna go on ahead and get on board.
Ben önden gemiye gidiyorum.
Idiot! Don't!
Aptal, sakın yapma!
Idiot!
Aptal!
Idiot Moss Head!
Aptal, Yosun Kafa!
Moss Head idiot!
Yosun Kafalı aptal!
You won't make it three steps alone in that forest without getting lost!
O ormanda tek başına üç adım bile atamazsın, kaybolursun!
Hey, look! It's Robin!
Hey, bakın! Robin!
Robin!
Robin-chan!
Hey, Robin!
Hey, Robin!
Hurry, hurry! Make a run for it! We stole some gold!
Çabuk, çabuk! Kaçıyoruz! Bir sürü altın çaldık!
Zip it, moron!
Kes sesini, sersem!
Try looking behind her!
Arkasına bak!
They're all coming back at once!
Hep birlikte geliyorlar!
There's a ton of them!
Koca bir ordu!
This is bad! This is bad! This is super bad!
Eyvah! Eyvah! Başımız büyük dertte!
And what's that? A huge cannon?!
O da ne? Dev bir top mu?!
It's gotta be!
Kesin öyle!
They came back all at once!
Demek topluca geliyorlar!
Hurry to the ship!
Gemiye koşun!
We can't stay here anymore!
Daha fazla kalamayız!
Check this out! We got a good haul!
Şuna bak! İyi bir vurgun yaptık!
The bag's stuffed! We're rich!
Çantalarımız dolu! Zenginiz!
What? They all have their bags on!
Ne? Hepsi çantalarını toplamış!
Don't tell me... they're leaving already?!
Yoksa hemen gidiyorlar mı?!
Hey, stop, you guys! Stop!
Hey, durun! Durun!
Hey! Stop! Stop, you guys!
Hey! Durun! Bekleyin, size diyorum!
See?! They caught us!
Gördünüz mü?! Fark ettiler!
Run!
Kaçın!
Time to strike a pose and make a speech!
Poz kesip durumu kurtarma zamanı!
You can ask us to stop all you want!
İstediğiniz kadar durmamızı söyleyin!
Yeah! Tell them, Usopp!
Evet! Konuş be, Usopp!
We risked our lives to come all the way to this sky island!
Canımızı ortaya koyarak geldik bu gökyüzü adasına!
That's right!
İyi dedin!
And we've found the legendary City of Gold!
Ve efsanevi Altın Şehir'i bulduk!
Robin! Hurry up! We'll get caught!
Robin! Çabuk! Bizi yakalayacaklar!
Would you really expect proud pirates like us to go back empty-handed?!
Onurlu korsanlar olarak ellerimiz boş dönmemizi mi bekliyorsunuz?!
What?! Caught?! What's he talking about?
Ne?! Yakalamak mı?! Neden bahsediyor bu?
All we want to do is thank them!
Sadece teşekkür etmek istiyoruz!
Hey miss, aren't you guys gonna take this gold?
Hey hanımefendi, altını almayacak mısınız?
I guess not!
İstemiyorlar!
– What?!
– Ne?!
Oh no!
Olamaz!
Run!
Kaçın!
– Hey! Wait!
– Hey! Bekleyin!
They're all after us! Too scary!
Hepsi peşimizde! Çok korkunç!
How was that?! Wasn't I cool?!
Nasıldı?! Havalı mıydım?!
Yeah! Well done!
Evet! İyi işti!
Robin my love! Hurry!
Robin-chwan! Acele et!
– Hey! Come back!
– Hey! Geri dönün!
Guys!
Millet!
Keep running all the way to the end of the sky!
Gökyüzünün sonuna kadar durmayın!
– Yeah!
– Tamam!